The inside story of the world's greatest manhunt.
Patriots Day is a action, crime, drama film directed by Peter Berg.
In the aftermath of an unspeakable act of terror, Police Sergeant Tommy Saunders joins courageous survivors, first responders
and investigators in a race against the clock to hunt down the Boston Marathon bombers before they strike again.
Sgt. Tommy Saunders, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Commisioner Ed Davis, played by John Goodman.
Sgt. Jeffrey Pugliese, played by J.K. Simmons.
Richard DesLauriers, played by Kevin Bacon.
Carol Saunders, played by Michelle Monaghan.
Dzhokhar Tsarnaev, played by Alex Wolff.
Patriots Day is a 2016 American action thriller film based on the Boston
Marathon bombings in 2013 and the subsequent terrorist manhunt.
Directed by Peter Berg and written by Berg, Matt Cook, and Joshua Zetumer, the film
is based on the book Boston Strong by Casey Sherman and Dave Wedge.
It stars Mark Wahlberg, Kevin Bacon, John Goodman, J.
Simmons, and Michelle Monaghan.
It marks the third collaboration between Berg and Wahlberg,
following Lone Survivor and Deepwater Horizon.
The title refers to Patriots' Day, the Massachusetts state
holiday on which the Boston Marathon is held.
Principal photography began on March 29, 2016, in New York City, and also
filmed in Boston, Los Angeles, New Orleans, and Philadelphia.
The film premiered on November 17, 2016, at the AFI Fest.
Distributed by CBS Films via Lionsgate, It was released in Boston, New York and Los Angeles
on December 21, 2016, followed by a nationwide expansion on January 13, 2017.
It received positive reviews for Berg's direction and the performances of its
cast, and grossed $52 million against a $45 million budget.
The film was chosen by the National Board of Review
as one of the top ten films of 2016.
The film explores themes of boston, massachusetts,
massachusetts, police chief, based on true story, terrorism.
The tone is emotional and intense.